A Guide to the Franklin P. Hall Papers, 1976-2009
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Franklin P. Hall Papers, 1976-2009
The Library of Virginia
44280
16.5 cubic feet (37 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frank Hall, Richmond.
Biographical Information
Franklin Perkins "Frank" Hall was born in Amelia County, Virginia on 13 December 1938. He earned a bachelor of science degree from Lynchburg College, and a masters in business administration and law degree from American University. While attending American University, Hall served on the staff of Sen. and Vice-President Hubert Humphrey. He then moved to the Department of Housing and Urban Development. Hall and his wife opened a law practice in Richmond in 1969, and he then opened Commonwealth Bank in 1986, which later merged with First Community Bank. In 1975, Hall was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates, representing the 69th District. He served as Minority Leader from 2002 to 2007. Hall retired from the state legislature in 2009, and was appointed to the board of the Virginia Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control by Governor Tim Kaine.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1976-2009, of Franklin P. "Frank" Hall (b. 1938) of Richmond, Virginia, who represented the 69th District in the Virginia House of Delegates. Includes legislative files, constituent correspondence, office files, campaign files, House Democratic Caucus files, and special media.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Legislative Files.
Series II. Constituent Correspondence.
Series III. Office Files.
Series IV. Campaign Files.
Series V. House Democratic Caucus Files.
Series VI. Special Media.
Contents List
- Series I. Legislative Files., Extent: 8 boxes. (Box 1-8)
  The legislative files include drafts and final copies of bills, resolutions, and budget amendments introduced by Hall, correspondence with constituents, fellow legislators, advocacy groups, and government officials, background materials, clippings, notes, memoranda, summaries, legal opinions, roll call votes, and impact statements. There are also patron and co-patron reports generated by the House Clerk which give summmaries, dates, and actions taken by the General Assemby on legislation introduced or co-sponsored by Hall. Areas of interest reflected in the legislation he introduced include school truancy and dropout prevention, state employees, and Richmond city government. In addition, there are issue files related to the 69th District, including annual and financial reports of various organizations, correspondence, clippings, brochures and handbooks, proposals, and program summaries. The bulk of the legislative files cover the years 1996-1997 and 2007-2009.
  - 1976-1987
    - Patron Reports. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1986
    - "Capitol Action". (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1987
    - Popular Bills. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1989
    - Law Enforcement/Public Safety Funds - Richmond. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1990
    - Voting Record. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1991
    - Redistricting. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1992
    - Voting Record. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1993
    - Session Highlights. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1994
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1996
    - H.B. 559 - Limited Partnerships. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 691 - Alcoholic Beverage Licenses - Suspension or Revocation. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 806 - Powers of Service Districts. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - H.B. 807 - Personnel Act (Bumping). (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 986 - Powers and Duties of School Boards. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - H.B. 987 - Local Community College Boards Service Delivery Boundaries. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 988 - Worforce Transition Act of 1995. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - H.J.R. 20 - Commending Constantine NIcholas Dombalis. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - H.J.R. 120 - Evaluate and Review the Judicial Inquiry and Review Commission. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - H.J.R. 240 - Evaluate Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Substance Abuse Services. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - H.J.R. 241 - School Dropout Prevention. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - H.J.R. 343 - Hate Crimes and Acts of Bigotry. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Alternative Fuel Revolving Fund. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Biotechnology Research Park - VCU. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Broad Rock Baptist Church. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Combined Sewer Overflow Matching Fund. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Commission on Local Government - Executive Director Salary. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Court-Appointed Attorneys and Physicians Fee Increase. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Doctor of Pharmacy Program at VCU. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Drug Court Pilot Program - City of Richmond. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Even Start. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Fund-Split Error - VCU Steam Plant. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Healthy Families Intitiative. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College Renovations. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Korean Cultural and Senior Center. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Library of Virginia. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Long Term Care - State Employees. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Medical Education Program at VCU. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Nursing Home Resident Displacement. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Progressive Disease - Medicaid Appeal. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Regional Competitiveness Act Incentive Fund. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Retirees' Health Insurance. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Richmond City Mayor-at-Large Election Implementation Panel. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - School Dropout Prevention. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Split Funding - VCU and MVC. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Sports Medicine and Athletic Departments at VCU. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - State Police Salaries. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Biotechnology Research Park Short Term Loans. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Health Information System. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Historical Society. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1997
    - H.B. 1908 - Property Tax Exemption - Moose Lodge. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - H.B. 1934 - Sales and Use Tax Exemptions. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - H.B. 1935 - Richmond City Charter. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - H.B. 1936 - Education of Suspended, Excluded, or Expelled Students. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - H.B. 2045 - Establishment of City Personnel Systems. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - H.B. 2149 - Returning Portion of Oakwood Cemetery to City of Richmond. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - H.B. 2151 - Alternative Education Programs. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - H.B. 2234 - Motor Vehicle Liability Insurance. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - H.B. 2275 - Sale of Delinquent Tax Lands. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - H.B. 2276 - Carbon Monoxide Exclusions. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - H.B. 2360 - Official Song of the Commonwealth. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - H.B. 2426 - Virginia Personnel Act. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - H.B. 2510 - Tax Credit for Caregivers. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 2885 - Vehicle Window Tinting or Shading. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 2886 - Definition of Club. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 2887 - Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 2888 - Cable Television. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - H.J.R. 629 - Expulsions and Suspensions of Public School Students. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cash Proffer - Home Builders. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Children's Museum. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - City Treasurer's Office via VRS - Bill Leighty. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Department for the Aging - Case Management. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Hold" File. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Oakwood Cemetery - Confederate Section. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Possible Legislation. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Traumatic Brain Injuries. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Use of Inpatient Hospital Beds for Furnishing Skilled Care Services. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 2005
    - Virginia Institute for Public Policy/Citizens Against Government Waste. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 2006
    - Medicare Event - Trinity Baptist Church,15 May 2006. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 2007
    - Appropriations Committee. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Berry, Howard M. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chief Medical Examiner's Annual Report. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Home Building Association of Richmond - General Assembly Breakfast, 27 November 2007. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - House Joint Resolutions. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Joint Leadership Council of Veterans Service Organizations. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Judgeships. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Massey Cancer Center - Voluntary Contributions. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mental Health. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Naturopathic Physician Licensure. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Financial Perspective. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 2008
    - H.J.R. 91 - Joint Subcommittee Studying Private Institutions Addressing Virginia's Educational and Workforce Needs. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - S.B. 30 - Virginia Economic Bridge, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - S.B. 61 - Workers' Compensation Alternative Dispute Resolution Systems. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - S.B. 588 - Payday Loan Act. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - S.B. 729 - Retail Sales and Use Tax/Northern Virginia Transportation. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - S.J.R. 122 - Rapid Transit Service Network Study. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Assisted Living Facilities Inspections. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities (APVA) - John Marshall House. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bluefield College. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Cash Proffers. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Central Virginia Area Housing Market Annual Report. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Certificates of Commendation - Scholar and Honor Roll Students. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 896 Appeal - Opinion, 29 February 2008. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Chesterfield County Election Process Review. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Chesterfield County Cash Proffers. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - CHIP of Virginia. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Community Development Authorities Act - Revisions. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Consumer Action Handbook. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Disability Services System in Virginia Biennial Assessment. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Dominion Fuel Rate Proposal. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Dulles Corridor Metrorail Extension. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Dulles Greenway Toll Increases. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fifty States Bill Information Database. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Joint Commission on Health Care. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Judgeships (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Legislative Summaries. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Lumpkin's Slave Jail. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Maryland Health Insurance Partnership. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Medical Transportation. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - NARAL Pro-Choice Virginia. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Parole - Concerned Taxpayers Coalition. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Peck Property Environmental Cleanup - Portsmouth. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Perel, Jonathan S. - Right of Way. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Press Conference, 26 September 2009. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Prison Growth and Costs. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Project Discovery. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Public Notices/Newspapers. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Public Transportation and Rail Programs Allocation Summary. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Regional Transit Authority. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Resolutions. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Richmond Association of Realtors. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Richmond City Annual Financial Report. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Richmond City Audit. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - School Dropout Prevention and Truancy. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Singh, Sukhbir. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - State of the Commonwealth - Talking Points. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Tax Department Voluntary Check-Off Legislation. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Troutman, Clifton J. III. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - United Food and Commercial Workers Union. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Association of Community Service Boards - Annual Report. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Cancer Plan. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Virginia Legislative Record." (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Municipal League - Statewide Transportation Funding Initiative. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Retirement System - Annual Financial Report. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Retirement System Asset Recovery Counsel. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Voter Registrars Association of Virginia. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - William and Mary Board Appointees. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 2009
    - H.B. 1600 - Veterans Admission to Colleges Amendment. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 1781 - Juvenile Records Sharing. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 1882 - Richmond Metropolitan Authority. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 2131 - Gang-Free Zones. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 2132 - Housing for Local Employees. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 2336 - Prohibiting Delivery of Unsolicited Newspapers. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 2396 - Advance Medical Directives. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 2408 - Community Development Authorities. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 2513 - Mob Violence in Schools. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 2661 - Recordation Tax Exemption. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - S.B. 807 - Mobile Camps and Other Railway Work Facilities. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - S.B. 1534 - Central Virginia Regional Transportation Authority. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - S.J.R. 280 - Gubernatorial Appointments. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - S.J.R. 328 - JLARC Post-Election Audits Study. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Adjusters International. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Amputated Lives: Coping With Chemical Sensitivity by Alison Johnson. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Anti-Arbitration Bill (H.R. 3010, S. 1782). (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Bennett, William - Resolution. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Bon Secours Richmond Health Care Foundation. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Center for Education Reform. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Coalition for Mentally Disabled Citizens of Virginia. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Commonwealth Education Poll. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - ElderHomes. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Equality Virginia. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Glass Replacement - 626 East Broad Street. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Independent Cities/Deletion in Numerous Statutes. (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Judicial Vacancy - Chesterfield County. (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Kaine Appointments. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Legislative Publications Checklist. (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Manchester Courthouse Construction. (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Medicolegal Death Investigations Staffing. (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Norfolk State University. (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Planning District Commissions. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Ballet. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "Session Highlights". (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Shockoe Center. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Smoke-Free Virginia. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Art Education Association. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commission for the Arts. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Department for the Aging. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Fire Service Needs Assessment. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Volkswagen. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Washington Center for Internships and Academic Seminars. (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series II. Constituent Correspondence., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 8-14)
  The constituent correspondence dates from 2004 to 2009, and is arranged by year, and thereunder by subject or date. Due to privacy concerns, some of the correspondence is not available for use. The subjects represented relate to issues of interest to citizens in the 69th District, including awards and resolutions, assistance with government agencies and departments, infrastructure issues, and support or opposition to specific legislative issues before the General Assembly concerning abortion, education, discrimination, genocide, payday loans, transportation, and other subjects. There is also correspondence related to Hall's service as House minority leader, and his retirement from the General Assembly and appointment to the board of the Virginia Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control.
  - 2004-2005
    - School Principals. (Box 8, Folder 12-14)
  - 2005
    - Constituents (N-Z). (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - 2006
    - Constituents. (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Constituents (A-L). (Box 9, Folder 4-7)
    - Constituents (M-Z). (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 2007
    - Constituents (A-J). (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
    - Constituents (A-J). (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Constituents (F-Z). (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
    - Minority Leader Support. (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Transportation. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 2007-2008
    - Abortion/Birth Control. (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
    - Discrimination. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Education. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Environment. (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
    - Insurance/Funding. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 11, Folder 7-12)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Payday Loans. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 2008
    - Constituents (A-E). (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
    - Constituents (F-P). (Box 12, Folder 7-10)
    - Constituents (Q-Z). (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - 2009
    - Constituents (A-L). (Box 13, Folder 3-6)
    - Constituents (M-Z). (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
    - Farewell. (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
- Series II. Constituent Correspondence., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 8-14)
  - 2004-2005
    - School Principals. (Box 8, Folder 12-14)